Hello, my name is Amy LaViers and welcome
to our first of seven glue lectures.
The point of this lecture, and we're
going to do one each week,
is to connect what Dr.
Egerstedt has done in the lectures to the
quizzes for each week.
So here, you'll get helpful hints about
the quizzes and we'll kind of clarify and
repeat a few key concepts.
so this is just meant to help you.
We'll do one a week and also be
moderating Q&A forums if you have further
questions or need more guidance in the,
in the course material.
So here, this is the first Glue Lecture
and we're going to be covering Dynamical
Models today and this is really tailored
to help with quiz one.
So [COUGH] I want to start with a picture
of how we've kind of first are introduced
to derivatives.
We typically think of, you know, if we
have this function x=t^2, we think of
this graph where we have x here on the
y-axis and t here on the x-axis.
And we think of this function as kind of
a line on a graph and we know if we take
the derivative of t^2, we get 2t,
we get this straight line now for the
first derivative,
and then our second derivative, which
sort of see this straight line.
And so, this is definitely a useful way
of thinking about derivitaves,
but in this, in this lecture I want us to
kind of go beyond these lines on a graph
and think of these equations as
describing something that's moving.
So I'm going to replay this once.
Here, we have this ball moving in space,
right? Now, the axis don't mean anything
necessarily and we just have this
animation that it's moving or we can
think of our position here as x according
to t^2.
So, we can think of this as our axis, we
have this one single axis,
and the, the way that the ball is moving
is described by these equations here on
the left.
And we can kind of ask the question of
how does the ball know how to move? So if
these equations are describing the
movement that we're seeing and we can
think of this as a system kind of what's
going on? So to look at that, let's
imagine our ball in a discrete world.
And we can remember from lecture that we
can figure out how these continuous
equations translate into discrete time
using this taylor first order taylor
approximation.
Let's choose our delta t to be 0.5
seconds, and now, we can take this
previous system, where we had x dot
equals 2t.
We can figure out what the equation in
discrete time is to describe how the ball
should move.
So, here, we have this.
We can think of it as an update equation,
right? The next state is given by this
equation and it's a function of the
current state.
So, to see how the ball moves, let's
increment k.
We started here at zero, now k=1,
we take the past state, and we add the
current value of k.
Again, if we increment k to 2, we can see
that we take our past state, we add two,
we get,
we're now at x=3, right? And so forth.
So again, if we do it, and we can see
that, as we move, the ball is moving
fast, you know, more blocks each time,
so it's moving faster and faster. And
back to continuous time, we can see that
this is actually the equation that tell
us how the ball is moving.
It's speeding up as it goes along and
it's moving according to this equation x
dot, and this, is a dynamical model.
In addition to this description, this
update rule, this differential equation,
if we have an initial condition, so we
know where our ball needs to start.
Let's see if I can play this again.
We see that, this is what happens,
and so, we think of this as a dynamical
model and this is how we want to think
about differential equations in this
course.
So, an example.
What should we see when we see this? The
first thing to do when we see a plot is
always look at the axis.
We can see here that this is x versus
time.
We can see that we start at some non-zero
initial condition and we can see that
when that happens, we start to move and
we move kind of, we, we don't move in a,
at a constant rate, right?
If we moved at a constant rate, we would
see this straight line, but we can see
that actually what's happening is we're
speeding up as we go, as time increases,
and so, we can infer certain things about
what x dot looks like, then.
Right? So x dot is going to be something
that increases with time.
And, in fact, here, what we have is that
x dot is 2t.
So this is at a plot that we just saw
animated with the pink ball.
So, next, what we might see, is we might
be presented with a,a dynamical model.
What should be think when we see this?
Well, first of all, these x of t's,
we'll sometimes just write them as x as a
sort of shorthand.
And, what we can try to ask about this
model is what does x of t look like? So,
what's the trajectory described by this
system? And, what happens at time equal
to infinity, right? And that means, what
happens after a long time to this system?
So, if we want to find x of t, we just
need to integrate our differential
equation or sometimes what we can do is
just guess a trajectory a form for x of
t, and then check, and the way you check
is just by differentiating.
So here, this is pretty easy, right?
We can see that when we differentiate
x^2/2, we get x.
So this is the form of x of t.
It's going to be some kind of problem,
right?
And the second thing that we might ask
this idea of what happens long term to
the system is just a matter of
considering what happens when x stops
moving?
Because when x stops moving, we're stuck,
right? That's where our system ends up.
So, if we plug in what it means for x to
stop moving is for x dot to be zero.
If we plug this in to our dynamical
system,
we find that that means that x=0.
So long term with this system, what's
going to happen is x is going to rest at
zero and we call this an equilibrium
point,
because the system isn't moving at this
point.
So, that wraps up our lecture.
good luck with Quiz 1, and I'll see you
at the forums.